# Kristin De Salme

Phone: (210) 445-2192 | Email: kristin.desalme@gmail.com | San Antonio, TX

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristin-desalme/ Portfolio: https://kr1istin.github.io/portfolio react/

GitHub: https://github.com/KR1ISTIN

As a FullStack developer and dental hygienist, I offer excellent communication and teamwork skills, along with a keen eagerness and willingness to learn on this journey. The transition from oral health care to programming may seem unexpected, but I thrive on challenges, and web development provides the perfect canvas. I look forward to contributing my diverse experiences and enthusiasm to a new team and making a meaningful impact in the field.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML5, BASH
- Frameworks/Libraries: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Node.js, Express.js, React, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Bulma, Tailwind
- Databases: PostGresQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose
- Tools/Technologies: RESTful APIs, Maven, Docker, Microservices, JWT, Auth0, OAuth2, Bycrpt, GraphQL, Jest, Object-oriented programming, Heroku, Git, IntelliJ, pgAdmin4, MySQL Workbench, MVC Pattern
- **Project Management:** Team Collaboration, Communication, Agile Development, Scrum, Sprint, Kanban, Jira, Github Projects, Wireframming, GithubActions CI/DC Pipeline
- AWS: IAM, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, AWS RDS, S3

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Backend Developer ARP Roofing and Remodeling

2024-Present Remote

Contracted to create an app that is a central source for customer related data.

#### **Key Accomplishments:/In Progress**

- Reduced latency in lead creation by enabling sales reps to quickly input leads on the go
- Effectively created a central customer MySQL database with access for customer manipulation
- Reducing operational debt by integrating multiple systems together
- Implementing security best practices

Volunteering to help a childhood cancer nonprofit. Built a key-single page featuring update operations, database consultation and implementation, and mentoring in Git versioning control, and maintenance in code base.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- Collaborated with team to refine database architecture, ensuring efficiency
- Successfully trained my partner in Git versioning control, fostering collaborative and efficient development environments
- Successfully implemented RESTful APIs using Django and Python for user implementation
- Enhancing cleanliness in code base by addressing errors, with unit tests will be added

Dental Hygienist TruSmile Dentistry

2017-Present San Antonio, TX

2023-Present

Remote

Perform dental cleanings and educate patients on how to maintain excellent oral hygiene.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Established a strong rapport with patients through active listening, empathetic communication, and personalized care, nurturing trust and comfort that contributed to improved patient cooperation and dental experience.
- Collaboration with dental colleagues, sharing insights and providing assistance in complex cases, thereby creating a cohesive team environment that improved patient care and satisfaction.
- Took *leadership* of training my colleagues, teaching the important skills and knowledge which elevated the team's expertise and provided a more valuable workflow
- Moved to lead hygienist after 1 year

## **PROJECTS**

### MealMappr

#### Github Repo Link

## **Deployed Link to MealMappr**

MealMappr, a team project, that allows access for users to manage their personalized meal plans

#### Role: FullStack and Project Management

Implemented Models, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, Login/Logout functionality, Scrum Master, UI design for modals

**Tools/Technologies:** Heroku, HTML, JavaScript, Node, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, TailWind, Full Calendar, Bycrpt, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, KanBan, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

#### YardGems

## **Github Repo Link**

## **Deployed Link to YardGems**

YardGems, a team project, utilizing the MERN Stack. Allowing users to search and post garage sales

## **Role: FullStack and Project Management**

Implemented React Google Maps API, Models, GraphQL, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, secure Login/Logout functionality, partial implementation UI design, Scrum Master

**Tools/Technologies:** React, React Router DOM, Heroku, Mongoose, JavaScript, React Google Maps API, GraphQL, MaterialUI, Express.js, Node.js, Apollo Server, JWT, Bycrpt, HTML, CSS, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, Kanban, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Master Java, Spring 6 and Spring Boot 3 with JDBC, JPA,

May 2024

## Security, Docker and Microservices with Telusko

A 42-hour course in mastering Java, Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, AOP, with the addition of Docker and Microservices

### Certificate, Full Stack Web Development: UTSA

**July 2023** 

A 24-week, project driven course, in full stack JavaScript Web Development Certification

# Associate, Dental Hygiene: Concorde Career College

May 2017

A 18-month accelerated program, focusing on oral hygiene and clinical care

Diploma, Dental Assisting: Concorde Career College

Feb 2014